Tottori
Hakuro
（加納(かのう)）
大会に懸ける意気込み …ですか？
My motivation for the tournament?
Yes, you're the national treasure Okanehira,
（リポーター）はい　国宝 大包平(おおかねひら)
白楼相撲部ナンバー２の—
Hakuro sumo club's #2,
so we'd like to hear from you, Kano-kun.
加納君からも是非
I don't know if "motivation"
is the right word,
（加納）意気込みと言えるかどうか
分かりませんが—
but I can tell you what I don't like.
単純にイヤなんですよ 負けるのが
And that's losing.
I stood by my father's side and watched
（加納）
父の横で ずっと見てきましたから
as countless teams had their dreams crushed.
たくさんのチームの夢が
終わる瞬間を
Sumo is a cruel sport.
残酷な競技なんですよね 相撲って
Right...
（リポーター）はい…
You can train hard
all three years of high school,
（加納）高校３年間 全てを懸けて
努力しても 終わるときは一瞬です
and it can be over in a moment.
If you lose, all that toil was for nothing.
負けたら 全てが無意味になる
I don't want my team to know
what that feels like.
こいつらに 負けたときの思いを
味わってほしくない
（加納）だから そういう思いは…
（リポーター）ウッ…
So I'm going to make sure...
全部 相手に味わってもらいます
it's our opponents who experience that pain.
Bout 19
"Weak Spirit, Strong Will"
I wonder if Kano's gonna lose...
（四方田(よもだ)）
加納のヤツ 負けねえかな
（澤井(さわい)）えっ？
（四方田）あいつ 相撲を
楽しいと思ってないんじゃない？
It doesn't seem like he really enjoys sumo.
Sosuke and the other national treasures
（四方田）草介(そうすけ)とか
ほかの国宝の連中はさ—
根っこの部分には
相撲を愛する心があるじゃん
have a special place
in their hearts for sumo.
なのに あいつだけは何か違う
But he's different, somehow.
父親がどうとか チームがどうとか
外にばかり理由を求める
He talks about his father and his team...
Always other people.
What about himself?
自分自身は どうなんだよ？
そういうヤツって どこの世界でも
一流には なれなくね？
Guys like that never reach the top,
whatever field they're in.
なのに あいつは強いんだよ
国宝なんだよ
Still, he's strong. He's a national treasure.
つまり 天才ってことなのかね
ヤダヤダ
Maybe that makes him a genius.
Good grief.
（澤井）
レスリングから転向して—
Kunisaki, the former wrestler who's been
tearing up the sumo ring, is much the same.
土俵を荒らし回る國崎(くにさき)も
大概ですけどね
But in terms of raw sumo ability,
Kano's the scarier of the two.
（四方田）
単純に相撲の才能で言ったら—
加納のほうが
底知れない怖さがあるよ
（桐仁(きりひと)）２連敗　もう あとがねえ
Two losses.
It's do or die.
We've got our backs against the wall,
so Kunisaki-san can't take risks here.
追い詰められた この状況では
國崎さんも慎重にならざるをえない
We're at a serious disadvantage.
圧倒的に不利だ
（審判）はっきよい！
（千比路(ちひろ)）ウウッ！
Spirit!
（男性１）おお！　鋭い！
（千比路）グッ…
A sharp strike!
Kano-san's using his killer stance!
（榎木(えのき)）
早くも加納さんの必勝パターンだ
It's a half stance that's defensively strong.
（榎木）半身の構え 堅守の型
He absorbs his opponent's force
相手の圧力に耐えながら
空いたスペースで自在に投げを放つ
and uses the extra room
it gives him to execute a throw.
逃げてもムダだ
You won't get away!
Seriously, dude, how much did you steal?
（沙田(さだ)）まったく…
手癖が悪いにも程があるよ
National Treasure Eater,
that's Odenta's Flash Attack you're using!
国宝喰(ぐ)い 大典太(おおでんた)の閃光(せんこう)
This guy...
こいつ…
Hey, he's doing good!
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）
やるのぅ 千比路のヤツ！
Go!
（桐仁）いけ！
What's with this guy?
何なんだ？　こいつは
Why's he going hard on the offensive when
losing this bout will see them eliminated?
負けたら終わりの状況で
どうして ここまで大胆に…
Don't act so surprised, Number Two.
（千比路）
ビクビクしてんじゃねえよ
ナンバー２
You're strong, no doubt about it.
（千比路）確かに てめえは強(つえ)えよ
You're a member of the top high school
sumo club in Japan, and it shows.
日本一の相撲部で
もまれ続けただけはある
でもよ その分
負けんのが 人一倍 怖(こえ)えんだろう？
But I bet...
that makes you all the
more fearful of losing.
Call it reckless or whatever you want,
無謀だろうが何だろうが—
but you can't break out of your shell
if you don't reach out to your fears.
怖え所に手ぇ伸ばさなきゃ
殻は破れねえ
He knows that better than anyone.
それを あいつは誰より知ってたよ
The "weakling" whose efforts
you called meaningless!
てめえが無意味と切り捨てた
弱いあいつはな
I'll show you...
見せてやるよ
身の程知らずの
バカが持つ底力をな！
just how strong people who don't
know their own limits can be!
Kano-san's getting pummeled!
（榎木）加納さんが押されてる！
（バトムンフ）フン…
Keep it up, Kunisaki!
（小関(おぜき)）いいぞ 國崎！
（桐仁）よし！
All right!
What's going on?
（金盛(かなもり)）どうなってんだ？
あの突きがコピーなら—
If he just copied that move,
大典太に負けなしの加納なら
防げるはずだろう？
Kano should be able to block it easy,
since he's never lost to Odenta.
It was never going to be an exact copy.
そりゃ
全く同じものにはなりませんよ
本家とは
体格もリーチも違い過ぎる
His build and reach are much too different.
But those differences...
でも そのズレが逆に—
have made it faster and given it
a different rhythm from the original.
本家以上の回転数と
独特のリズムを生んでいる
That strike is now a Chihiro Special.
あの突きは もう立派な
チヒロスペシャルっすよ！
Get a grip!
落ち着け！
大典太より速い分 威力は落ちる
His strikes are faster than Odenta's,
but they're not as hard!
I can knock them away!
（加納）はたき落とす！
（千比路）ンッ…
Lightning
High-Angle
Head Chop
Lightning
High-Angle
Head Chop
High-Angle Head Chop: Lightning!
Lightning
High-Angle
Head Chop
Good hit!
うまい！
He's dominating the high school number two!
（佑真(ゆうま)）
高校ナンバー２を翻弄してやがる！
Am I... about to lose?
負ける …のか？
He did it! Two years in a row!
（男性）決まった！　２連覇！
Tennoji takes the title of high
school yokozuna this year, too!
（男性）
高校横綱は 今年も天王寺(てんのうじ)だ！
ハハッ…
今年も かなわなかったか
I couldn't beat you this year either, huh?
Does facing a teammate
lower your intensity, Aki?
（天王寺）
仲間が相手じゃ燃えへんか？　アキ
You shone much brighter in middle school.
（天王寺）中学のほうが
今よりギラギラしとったで
俺に負けることに
慣れてもうた今よりな
Much brighter than now,
when you've gotten used to losing to me.
You've got to fight harder.
もっと張り合ってくれや
ライバルやろう
We're rivals, remember?
Don't overestimate me, Shido.
（加納）買いかぶるなよ 獅童(しどう)
Training beside you showed me
お前が そばにいたことで
思い知らされたんだよ
“お前には勝てっこない”って
that I had no hope of beating you.
You can laugh all you want.
笑いたきゃ笑え
But even so...
それでも
獅童の次に強いってことが—
Being second only to Shido...
Yeah!
is a source of pride for me!
ちっぽけな俺の誇りなんだよ！
（桐仁）あっ…
（小関）國崎！
Kunisaki!
I don't want to lose to anyone but Shido!
（加納）獅童以外には負けたくない
草薙(くさなぎ)にも お前にも負けない！
I won't lose to Kusanagi,
and I won't lose to you!
Being cornered lit a fire inside him.
追い込まれて 火がついたか
Kano-san always says
he's not as good as Shido-san.
加納さんは いつも—
獅童さんと自分を比べては
卑下するけど 僕らは知ってますよ
But we know the truth.
You love sumo, too!
あなたも相撲が好きだってこと
（２人の力み声）
（男性１）がっぷり四つだ！
He's got both hands on his belt!
Oh, no! He's been caught.
マズイ！　完全に捕まえられた
あの距離じゃ機動力を生かせない！
He can't use his agility at close quarters!
Damn, he's got both
sides of his mawashi belt!
（佑真）ああも両廻(りょうまわ)し
ガッチリ引かれちまったら…
Even Kunisaki-san doesn't have a technique
that'll shake off Okanehira's grip!
（桐仁）さすがの國崎さんでも
大包平相手に廻しを切る技術はない
There are no throws I can do
that'll get me out of this.
（千比路）この体勢から
俺が出せる投げ技はないか…
なら…
So...
I'll just bulldoze him out of the ring!
（千比路）土俵の外に出すまでだ！
Kunisaki is...
（金盛）國崎が…
（荒木(あらき)）寄り！？
...pushing him out?
（千比路）捕まったんじゃねえ
（加納）ウッ…
You didn't catch me.
I'm the one who caught you.
（千比路）俺が捕まえたんだ
（加納）クッ…
確かに てめえらに比べりゃ
日は浅いが—
It's true that I have less experience
than you, but in the sumo ring...
土俵の上での俺は
もう レスラーじゃねえ！
I'm not a wrestler anymore!
（千鶴子(ちづこ)）
今までの國崎さんなら—
Before, Kunisaki-san would've come up
with a way to break his grip and pull back.
どうにかして
離れる方法を考えていたはず
（千鶴子）
でも 今の國崎さんは違う
But that's not how he does things now.
He's making progress as a sumo wrestler.
今の１歩は 力士としての１歩
組み手も体格も五分
They're equal in physique and position.
Now it's just a battle of wills
between two sumo wrestlers.
２人の力士の
意地と意地のぶつかり合い
Why isn't he stopping?
なんで止まらない？
Instead of weakening,
衰えるどころか
むしろ 力が増していく！
he's applying more and more pressure!
（千比路）俺は 寄り切りってのは
好きじゃねえ　地味だからな
I don't like the front force-out.
It's so bland.
But...
でも…
Your back was anything but bland!
お前の背中は
全然 地味なんかじゃなかったよ
After seeing that look in your eyes,
あんな顔 見せられたらよ…
I can't whine and give up!
俺が 先に音(ね)を上げるわけには
いかねえんだよ！
（蛍(けい)）ハッ…
I know I said I wanted Kano to lose...
（四方田）俺 さっき 加納に
負けてほしいって言ったけどさ
やっぱ 國崎のほうが嫌いだわ
But I think I hate Kunisaki more now.
（歓声）
（審判）東の勝ち！
East side wins!
Kunisaki-kun wins by force-out!
（アナウンス）
寄り切りで 國崎君の勝ち！
（千比路）フン！
（千鶴子）なりふりかまわない寄り
An unflamboyant force-out...
Your bout might just have
had an effect on him.
三ツ橋(みつはし)君の頑張りに
影響されたのかもしれませんね
相撲を始めたのは
僕と同時なのにな
We picked up sumo at the same time.
ズルイや　カッコよすぎです
This isn't fair.
He's just too cool.
In the end, Kunisaki utterly destroyed him.
終わってみれば 國崎の完勝
Kano-san didn't have an answer.
加納さんは
いいとこなかったですね
We'll have to watch out for Kunisaki.
ヤバイな 國崎
どんどん強くなるよ
He just keeps getting stronger.
I don't believe it.
（兵藤(ひょうどう)）ホントに まいったぜ
（四方田）うん？
（兵藤）白楼にも大太刀(おおだち)にも
女子マネがいるってのに—
Both Hakuro and Odachi
have female managers.
なんでウチには
いねえんだろうな？
Why don't we have one?
えっ？　何の話？
Uh, what are you talking about?
（兵藤）ハハハハッ！
ありゃ 加納の自滅だな
Kano caused his own downfall.
Chihiro came at him like a bull
instead of being clever,
トリッキーなはずの千比路の
正面からの寄りに 一瞬 躊躇(ちゅうちょ)した
and Kano hesitated.
To put it another way, Chihiro
sniffed his chance and took it.
逆に言えば その一瞬の勝機を
逃さなかった千比路の嗅覚
（兵藤）
さすがは俺の背を見て育った男よ！
That's what watching me will do to someone!
Sorry I couldn't finish them off.
すまん みんな　決められなかった
（バトムンフ）フン…
（真田(さなだ)）出たな
That's their first-year Mongolian
exchange student, Batmönkh Batbayar.
モンゴル人留学生 １年
バトムンフ･バトバヤル
A high school team can only field
one foreigner in tournaments.
（真田）高校相撲の外国人枠は１名
And he took that spot as a first-year?
彼が１年にして
勝ち取ったってわけですか
どうりで あの ただならぬ殺気
That explains the intense vibes I'm getting.
And Dachi High is still teetering
on the edge of a cliff.
それに
ダチ高が崖っぷちなのは変わらねえ
何しろ ここまでの重大局面で—
Plus, that guy's never had to perform...
when everything's on the line like it is now.
あいつに回ってきたことは
ねえからな
Kunisaki!
（小関）國崎！
You really came through for us!
やっぱ頼れるぜ あんたは！
タハハハッ！　当然だろう　俺だぞ
'Course I did! Who d'ya think you're talking to?
Okay.
さて そろそろ
カッコイイところ見せてくれよ
Show us how awesome you can be, Gojo—
ごじょ…　オオッ！？
えっ？　な… 何か言った？
D-Did you say something?
佑真さん？
Yuma-san...
It's over.
終わった…
What are you getting nervous about, Gojo?!
（千比路）
今更 なんちゅう
顔してんだ 五條(ごじょう)！
You know what's riding on this, don't you?!
どういう状況か
分かってんだろう？
If you lose, it's all over for Dachi High!
お前が負けたら
ダチ高も終わりだ！
（佑真）アッ！
（千比路）俺たちの日本一の夢も
We won't be the best in Japan!
（佑真）ウッ！
（千比路）火ノ丸のプロへの夢も
And Hinomaru won't make
it to the pro league!
閉ざされちまうんだって！
ウグッ！
Hey, Kunisaki,
don't put so much pressure on him.
ちょ…　國崎
ダメだよ 追い詰めちゃ
Sorry, Yuma-san, this is because I lost.
ごめん 佑真さん
俺が負けたばっかりに…
O-Ozeki...
（佑真）お… 小関
What's this?
（男性１）何だ？
（男性２）大太刀がモメてるぞ
Dachi High's arguing.
Yuma...
（礼奈(れいな)）佑真…
（舟木(ふなき)たち）アア…
Ozeki lost because of the
two years I stole from him.
（佑真）小関が負けたのだって—
本を正せば 俺が あいつから
奪った２年間のせいなんじゃ…
Now, the team's dream,
and the shrimp's future...
それに この試合には
みんなの夢が…　チビの将来が…
Yuma.
（火ノ丸）佑真
This isn't some dire situation.
You've been handed a huge opportunity.
これはピンチじゃなくて
チャンスじゃねえのか
チャンス？
An opportunity?
そうだ
ずっと待ってたはずじゃねえか
He's right. This is what I've been waiting for.
To take back what was done.
“覆水を盆に返す”
小関に チビに 相撲部に
借りを返せる この時を
To Ozeki, Shorty, and the sumo club.
I can make it all right.
If I'm the type to tremble at that thought...
それで震えるのが俺なら
そういう俺をぶつけるしかねえ
then I'll just fight while trembling!
（佑真）フゥ…
I'm a member of
the Dachi High sumo club, too.
俺だってダチ高相撲部だ
I'm gonna carry my share of the load!
いろいろ背負わせてもらうぜ！
Yeah.
おう！
Mom, you should do what
he did and chill out, too.
（高荷(たかに)の息子）お母さんも
あれやって落ち着いたら？
（高荷）大丈夫
I'm fine.
My student will give it his all.
弟子が頑張ってんだぞ
目をそらすな
Do not look away.
You have to watch, no matter what happens.
見届けるんだ
どんな結果になろうとも
（バトムンフ）ハァ…
なんで こんなヤツなんかと
Why do I have to fight you?
Just so you know, I'm stronger than Kano-san.
言っとくけど
僕 加納さんより強いからね
I'm not here to play.
遊びじゃない
This is like a tryout for me.
僕にとって
ここは就職活動の場なんだよ
Each stable can only
have one foreign fighter.
ひと部屋につき
外国人力士は１人まで
With such a strict limit, I need to show how
strong I am to mark me out from the rest.
限られた枠に割り込むために—
僕は自分の強さを
アピールしないといけないんだ
And then, they give me you as an opponent.
なのに 相手は こんなヤツ…
もっと鬼丸(おにまる)とかと やりたかったな
I'd much rather have fought Onimaru.
Shut your mouth.
（佑真）うるせえ
（バトムンフ）うん？
I don't care what you're here for.
（佑真）
てめえの事情なんて知ったことか
I'm gonna push my team's dream forward,
even if it means eating a rock!
俺は 石にかじりついてでも
仲間の夢をつないでやる！
（審判）両者 手をついて！
Competitors, hands on the ground.
モンゴル相撲は土俵がないから—
Mongolian sumo doesn't use a ring.
The bout doesn't end
until one competitor falls.
相手を投げ崩すまで
勝負は終わらない
That's why Bat's a specialist in
getting up close and personal.
いわば
バトは組み技のスペシャリスト
That guy, on the other hand,
often loses in those situations.
一方 あの選手は
組まれると めっぽう弱い
We have a massive advantage in this bout.
この組み合わせ
圧倒的に こっちの有利だ
Good luck!
（礼奈）頑張れ！　佑真は強いよ！
You're strong, Yuma!
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
（桐仁）なっ…
（小関）突き！？
Strikes!
Here we go.
（バトムンフ）いいぜ
あんた 突きが得意なんだろう？
You specialize in strikes, right?
I'll beat you with strikes and
show your country how strong I am!
だったら その突きで勝って—
俺の強さを
全国にアピールさせてもらう
So you're as strong as a national treasure?
（佑真）お前も国宝級ってわけか
俺なんかが勝てるわけねえけど…
There's no way I should be beating you,
but it looks like I don't have a choice!
（佑真）
勝たなきゃいけねえんだよ！
There they are!
（西郷(さいごう)）出た！
（舟木）空手仕込みの突き！
His karate-style strikes!
Yuma-san!
（橋(はし)）佑真さん！
（佑真）ここで 俺が負けてみろ
I won't let myself lose!
If I lost, he'd regret his own
loss for the rest of his life!
あいつは
自身の負けを一生 悔やむ！
I'll lay down my life to make
Dachi High the best in Japan!
俺にとって ダチ高の“日本一”は
命を懸けるに値する！
So you're not here to play, either.
（バトムンフ）
そっちも遊びじゃない …か
なら こっちも つぶしがいがある！
That makes beating you more worthwhile!
The Mongolian, Batbayar...
I didn't expect him to fight like that!
モンゴル相撲のバトバヤルが…
予想外の展開だ
But if he's only using strikes,
けど 突き合いなら
佑真さんの土俵だよ！
Yuma-san can win!
These strikes are trouble.
この突きは やっかいだ
（佑真）大典太や國崎にも
連打では負けねえ！
My strikes are better than
Odenta's and Kunisaki's!
Striking is my route to victory!
突きこそが 俺の生きる道！
（バトムンフ）だが—
But a privileged competitor like you,
who has never had to fight for his place,
レギュラー争いもない ぬるま湯に
つかってきた あんたじゃ—
Tottori
Hakuro
俺には勝てない！
cannot hope to defeat me!
What was that? I dare you to say that again!
（フチェ）なんだと！？
もういっぺん言ってみろ！
（バトムンフ）
何度でも言ってやるよ
I'll say it as many times as you want.
You're weaker than me,
so I want your spot on the roster.
僕より弱いんだから
レギュラー代われよ
There's a limit of one foreigner per team.
（バトムンフ）外国人枠は
１つしかないんだからさ
（天王寺）そこまでや バト
強い･弱いの前に 礼儀を覚えんかい
That's enough, Bato.
Before talking about who's stronger,
you need to learn some manners.
（バトムンフ）礼儀？
Manners?
こいつが年上だから
譲ってやれっていうのか？
So I should defer to him
just because he's older?
I came here to become a pro!
僕はプロになるために
ここに来たんだ！
Unlike the rest of you,
I'm not here to play!
あんたらと違って
遊びじゃないんだよ！
I've never had a real bout with you.
あんたとは
ちゃんと やったことなかったね
If I beat you, will I get what I want?
あんたを倒せば
僕の待遇も変わりますか？
Hey, Bat, knock it off!
（加納）
おい バト！　いいかげんに…
There can be no respect until
we acknowledge each other, huh?
（天王寺）互いを認めんことには
敬意なんぞ生まれんか…
All right.
ええで
まずは互いを知ることから始めよか
Let's start by getting to know each other.
H-He's strong!
つ… 強い！
Am I losing? I can't be.
負ける？　ウソだろう？
こんな日本の学生に
Not to a Japanese student!
No!
イヤだ　イヤだ イヤだ！
ふざけんな！
No, no!
This can't be happening!
If I lose now, I can't become a yokozuna!
こんな所で負けてたら—
横綱になんてなれない！
（骨のきしむ音）
（天王寺）アホが…
You idiot.
（バトムンフ）アアッ…
（天王寺）まるで獣やな
You're like an animal.
You went too far when the
bout was already decided.
（加納）
極(き)まってるのにムチャしやがって！
You were too rough on him, bro!
（咲(さき)）兄貴も やりすぎや！
（天王寺）やりすぎ？
Too rough?
It would've gone the same way
if the roles were reversed.
互いが逆のシチュエーションでも
同じようになっとったわ
That's the kind of battle we were in.
そういう戦いやった
I couldn't let him win.
譲るわけにはいかへん
We're both idiots trying
to become yokozuna.
俺も こいつも
横綱目指すアホやからな
（天王寺）
フッ…　俺の寮部屋に空きがある
I have space in my dorm room.
I'll teach you everything from basic
manners to how to scrub a toilet.
礼儀作法からトイレ掃除まで 俺が
じきじきに仕込んだるわ バト
突き押しなら 勝てるとでも
思ったかよ？　ナメんな！
Did you think you could beat me in strikes?
Don't underestimate me!
The only people I acknowledge are Tennoji
俺が認めてるのは
天王寺の兄貴と—
and the teammates I've trained so hard with!
厳しい稽古を
共にした白楼の選手だけだ！
Batbayar's got the upper hand!
押してるのはバトバヤルだ！
He's avoiding the impacts
from Gojo's strikes!
五條の突きの衝撃も
うまく逃がしやがる
Yuma-san's landing more strikes, but...
手数では佑真さんが勝(まさ)ってるのに…
The accuracy of each blow...
（高荷）１発１発の正確性…
The number of critical hits
to his torso is on another level.
体の芯を捉える数が違う
Improved karate! Winding defense!
空手改法 巻き伏せ！
He's not falling.
（火ノ丸）動じない
Gojo-san should have an
advantage at that distance,
五條さんの得意な間合いで…
but he was completely outmatched!
（桐仁）完全に上を行かれた！
廻しを取られたら 終わり！
If he grabs my mawashi belt, it's over.
（バトムンフ）なぜ つかんだ？
How did he grab my wrist?
いや 隠れて見えないはずの
俺の手首を なぜ つかめた？
My wrist was hidden from view,
but he still grabbed it!
Yes!
（高荷）よし！
Sumo is fought at extremely close range.
（高荷）
相撲は 超至近距離の戦いだ
You can't see your opponent's whole body.
相手の全体を捉えることはできない
Even though you'll only have limited
information, you must anticipate
僅かな情報から
相手の動きを予測し—
your opponent's movements and
react accordingly even when blind.
視界の外でも
正確に動けるようになれ
You trusted my instructions
and geared your training to them.
私の教えを信じ
鍛え続けてくれた—
その愚直さこそが お前の武器だ
That simple-minded straightforwardness
is your biggest asset!
Reel-in lunge strike!
（佑真）手繰り追い突き！
This strike could do serious damage!
（バトムンフ）
この一撃は ヤバイ！
He dodged it!
かわされた！
So you were waiting for me
to grab your mawashi belt?
（バトムンフ）
廻しを取りに来る瞬間を狙う …か
Too bad it didn't help you!
残念だったな　ガラ空きだぜ！
You're wide open!
This is just... what I was waiting for!
この瞬間を ずっと待ってた！
This is what he was really after?!
（バトムンフ）
まさか 本当のねらいは…
Yes!
よし！
He feigned only being good at strikes,
“この選手には突きしかない
組み技はない”
and to further that lie,
he kept hidden all this while...
そう思わせるために
隠し続けた奥の手！
His trump card!
Gojo's grappling!
五條が組み技！？
Go!
（礼奈）いけ！
（小関）いけー！
Go!
いけー！
Three-Point Attack!
Three-Point Attack
Deformed
Triple-Attack
Force-Out
Call Out
Three-Point Attack
Deformed
Triple-Attack
Force-Out
Call Out
Three-Point Attack
Deformed
Triple-Attack
Call Out
Deformed Triple-Attack Force-Out:
Call Out!
The inside leg trip didn't work.
（火ノ丸）内掛けが不発！
まだ残りの二手がある！
He still has two points of contact!
I have to acknowledge him.
（バトムンフ）認めるしかない
He's not a national treasure...
国宝と呼ばれずとも
この男は強い！
but he's strong!
So what, though?
でも それが何だってんだ
With just one hand?!
片腕で！？
I'm going to be better than Tennoji.
（バトムンフ）
兄貴を超えるんだろう？
横綱になるんだろう？
I'm going to become a yokozuna!
I've talked a big game to
force myself to live up to it!
ここまで さんざん
でかい口をたたいてきたのは—
退路を断つためだ
If I don't win, I can't
stay in this country!
勝てなきゃ
この国に居場所はねえ！
（佑真）ウワッ！
（バトムンフ）ウオーッ！
Double Kick
Wolf
Fangs
Double Kick
Wolf
Fangs
Double Kick
Wolf
Fangs
Double Kick: Wolf Fangs!
Hang in there, Yuma!
こらえろ 佑真！
He forced it!
（加納）強引すぎた！
（バトムンフ）ンンッ…
I have to grab his belt!
（バトムンフ）早く廻しを！
（佑真）ンッ…
下段払い！
Lower block!
Reverse strike!
逆突き！
合わせ突き！
Joint strikes!
Inside leg trip!
内掛け！
The extreme form of the unconventional
sumo wrestler, Gojo-san!
異能力士！
これが五條さんの究極の姿！
Hit it, Yuma!
打て！　佑真！
Partial Lunge
Castle
Break
Punch
Partial Lunge: Castle Break Punch!
Partial Lunge
Castle
Break
Punch
Partial Lunge
Castle
Break
Punch
目が死んでいない！
There's still life in his eyes!
Neither the surprise grapple nor my
all-out strike combo did the trick?
奇襲の組み技でも 渾身(こんしん)の突きでも
やっぱり届かねえのか…
No...
いや…
Trust the team.
信じろ みんなを
Trust them and keep fighting.
信じて進め！
It's working. Don't stop!
効いてる　迷うな！
Keep hitting him until your arms falls off!
打て！　腕が ちぎれるまで！
Put it all on the line!
出し切れ！
みんながくれた俺の全てを！
Everything this team has given me!
Push!
押せー！
He fights hardest when he's doing it
for the sake of someone else.
（高荷）あいつは
人のためにこそ頑張れるヤツなんだ
Even now, you won't forgive yourself.
この先も お前は
自分を許すことはないだろう
But it's that seriousness
that I want to see rewarded.
でも そんな真面目な
お前だからこそ 報われてほしい
Win, Yuma. If not for anyone else,
then do it for yourself!
勝て　何より 佑真—
お前自身のために！
I hate stories about punks seeing the light.
（高荷）
嫌いなんだよ ヤンキー更生物語は
They always make me cry.
この泣かせに来る感じがさ
（審判）東の勝ち！
East side wins!
Don't you ever end up like him.
（高荷）
お前は あんなふうになるなよ
面倒くさいから
He's too much of a pain.
（咲）イヤなことがあると
ああして黙々と唐揚げ作んねんな
He always deep fries chicken when
he's got something on his mind.
I wonder what happened.
何があったんだろう？
These look good! I'm gonna have one.
うまそうやん　もらうで
オッ…　何味やねん？　これ
What did you use for seasoning?
I dipped it in a corn soup I'm trying out.
試作中のコンポタ味
I love fried chicken!
唐揚げ大好き！　僕も食べる！
I want one, too!
Those are waiting to be re-fried.
それは２度揚げ用だ
Oh, I've got it. It's because
he lost to Bato today.
ああ…　そういや 今日
バトに１本取られてたな
（天王寺）ウ〜ン…
Next Bout    "Onimaru Kunitsuna and Dojikiri Yasutsuna Go Again"
So that's the reason.
（咲）それでか…
（天王寺）ウ〜ン！